[Music]
welcome to the next episode of our
chocolate Series this one is a little
bit impromptu cuz I hadn't planned on
making this part the chocolate series
but I thought you know why not it's
chocolate ice cream it just happens to
be vegan so if you watch our videos
You'll possibly remember one I did
recently where I recreated a Ben and
Jerry's
core um on the tub they quite
specifically say that they used
condensed milk in their recipes it's not
in their recipe book those recipes they
they've never used those recipes ever in
their life I'm positive of it but if you
actually look on the tubs they they make
their ice cream in in an unusual way and
recreating that home I thought was
basically impossible but it's not you
you can actually do it and I'll link
below the video where our version of
their ice cream was just head and
shoulders above theirs but what it gave
me was an idea is can I create a vegan
ice cream using vegan condensed milk now
carnan make this in the UK it is made of
sugar water hydrolized rice flour
sunflower oil and oat
flour now one thing I did note when I
used this last time was it actually
added solids a good amount of solids to
a vegan ice cream and that's something
that a lot of vegan ice creams really
struggle with because you can't add the
normal kind of things where you get
solids from like milk powder and the
actual Dairy itself has a lot of solids
in it you don't get that so you have to
get solids from somewhere else there are
things like inulin you can use and other
various different powders but you know
I'm not a massive fan a lot of people
have reactions to inulin I don't at all
um you know I've not really used it that
often because I don't want cupboards
full of random
ingredients but this isn't so much a
random ingredient is you can go to your
supermarket and buy it so what we are
going to do today is make a vegan
Belgian chocolate Strat aella and I will
explain what the Strat aella is as we do
it so we are with our Dairy ice creams
we normally start with our milk here
we're going to start with our milk
substitute uh I'm going to talk about
that later in the video cuz I'm not a
huge fan of this one but anyway with
that in the pan we're going to add in
our Dex Dr now I've added a bit of
stabilizer to this again the stabilizers
are vegan most of them are I'm going to
say most of them not all of them but
most of them are you can add that in and
just gently warm that up add in your
entire can of carnation vegan condensed
milk and then just warm it up gently as
I've added the stabilizers really we
need this to come up to 60°
c as you're warming up add in your cocoa
powder and then just get it mixed nicely
combined so it's starting to bloom and
bring out that flavor and then the last
part we're going to do is add in our
chocolate this is a 56% the Rema
chocolate most 56% chocolate will be
vegan automatically just look at the
back of the pack all the ingredients
turn the heat off add your chocolate
stir it until it's nicely combined and
made a really nice silky base as you can
see here so once it's all completely
mixed and a beautifully silky base we're
going to put that in your container add
in two tubs of the elm Le plant-based
cream give it a nice final stir and then
put it in the fridge for a few hours to
chill
down once it's completely chilled you're
going to take it out and as normal just
give it one final stir loosen That Base
up cuz it will thicken somewhat in the
fridge but it does thin out nicely with
a good stir then put it in your machine
to churn as normal now because we're
doing a stratch aella what that means is
we're going to ribbon melted chocolate
through the ice cream as it's
churning so when your ice cream gets
right at the end of the churning process
you're going to take your chocolate now
if you see here our chocolate has
bloomed and that's due to the heat in
the house that we live in and that
blooming is the fat bloom type of Bloom
what that means is the cocoa butter has
come to the surface and solidified and
that's due to it coming up to a too
higher temperature
naturally basically means we've not
stored it very well either way you can
melt it down and use it as normal it has
no effect on the chocolate you use in
this recipe
we've melted it in the microwave and
then added just a little bit of coconut
oil to loosen it up and that will help
that solidifier at the right rate in
your ice cream and then take that to
your ice cream machine and just gently
ribbon that in as you can see it starts
to solidify and gets nice small little
pieces of that chocolate scattered
throughout your ice cream base another
couple of minutes and then we're going
to take it out put it in a tub and put
it in the freezer for a few
[Music]
hours so here we go big old fat tub of
chocolate ice cream let's
see how this one turned out I'm totally
unprepared like haven't got my bowl
haven't got my scoop let's dig some out
and see
that looks
good it's it's bloody hot
again it Scoops really well chocolate
ice cream if you make ice cream
professionally or at home or whatever
chocolate ice cream is notorious for
going harder than other ice cream why is
that it's because there is usually a
higher level of solids in the ice creams
themselves and that tends to mean it
goes harder you can fight that by adding
some invert sugar dextrose glucose
golden syrup you know corn syrup those
kind of things you can introduce those
and it will soften up a little bit which
is why I added dextrose into this rather
than table sugar or sucros it has a much
more effect of keeping things soft you
can add vodka if you want to yarn so
let's try some of this vegan Belgian
chocolate Strat Ella and see what it's
[Music]
like that that is
immense Strat aella
it means that you
get a piece of chocolate in every bite
and henar Belgian chocolate that's
actually how they do it they they ribbon
the chocolate through so you get loads
of little flexs in
there the texture is
perfect there there's no ice to the
palette it's a nice strong chocolate
flavor but not
bitter oh that is good this thankfully
this is the the milk substitute that I
used just grab a little glass out of the
covered I want to show you the color
DK I want to show you the color
obviously you know what color milk is
it's milk colored it's
white this stuff is like
yellow it's really watery then if you
can see it in there it's got a real
strong tinge of yellow it kind of looks
like watered down
egg has no smell to it at
all it tastes all right actually it
tastes okay it it doesn't really taste
of anything
it's it is oh it's got quite a
list it's water pea protein chory root
fiber sugar sunflower oil acidity
regulator Tri calcium phosphate natural
flavorings doesn't tell you what they
are couple of vitamins and caragan for a
stabilizer I didn't try this when we
were making it it just looked hideous
but actually I might change my mind
about it I don't I don't know where it
comes from where does it come from if
you know where this stuff comes from let
us know in the comments
below but this ice cream is exceptional
if you're looking for a vegan chocolate
with you know Strat Strat aella I can't
say it
um scattered throughout you are not
going to go wrong with this recipe this
is the second one I've done with these
in vegan form I'll put a link to the
strawberry haand Dar that we copied
below that was our absolute success
excuse me this one is just as much of a
success so I am really impressed with
this stuff
and I might make this my vegan staple
for ice cream moving
forward who knows anyway thanks very
much for watching don't forget to like
And subscribe and we'll see you next
time
[Music]